<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on Liva | Personal blog template</title>
    <link>https://zarxstar.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on Liva | Personal blog template</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:07:47 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://zarxstar.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mind Toolbox</title>
      <link>https://zarxstar.github.io/blog/post-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:07:47 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zarxstar.github.io/blog/post-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-map-is-not-the-territory&#34;&gt;The Map is Not the Territory&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The map is not the territory reminds us that our mental models of the world are not the same as the world itself. It cautions against confusing our abstractions and representations with the complex, ever-shifting reality they aim to describe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Writing Contests: Why Every Student Should Participate</title>
      <link>https://zarxstar.github.io/blog/post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:07:47 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zarxstar.github.io/blog/post-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s competitive academic and creative landscape, writing contests offer students an invaluable opportunity to showcase their talent, refine their skills, and gain recognition. Participating in writing contests can shape a young writer’s confidence, creativity, and future opportunities. For aspiring writers, researchers, or thinkers, these competitions provide more than accolades; they provide a platform to make their voices heard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Scientific Mindset Toolbox</title>
      <link>https://zarxstar.github.io/blog/post-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:07:47 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zarxstar.github.io/blog/post-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;relativity&#34;&gt;Relativity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Relativity is the idea that our perceptions and judgments are not absolute but are shaped by our unique vantage points and frames of reference. It’s the understanding that our experiences are subjective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extemp Questions</title>
      <link>https://zarxstar.github.io/blog/post-1.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 10:07:47 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zarxstar.github.io/blog/post-1.1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;topics-for-the-week-of-december-16-22-2024&#34;&gt;Topics for the Week of December 16-22, 2024&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;us-topics&#34;&gt;US Topics&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Is a “hands off” approach to the situation in Syria the best course of action for the United States?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Will president-elect Trump’s foreign policy make Latin America a bigger priority?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you were the writer of president-elect Trump’s inaugural address, what points would you emphasize?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Is the Black Lives Matter movement getting weaker?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Should President Biden give Dr. Anthony Fauci a pre-emptive pardon?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Would the defeat of Peter Hegseth’s nomination embolden opposition to other Trump appointees?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Should the Social Security Fairness Act be passed?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Are the drone sightings in New Jersey a national security threat?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Should Ron DeSantis appoint Lara Trump to the U.S. Senate?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Why is the U.S. fertility rate in decline?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;international-topics&#34;&gt;International Topics&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Can Bayrou succeed where Bernier failed?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How will Assad’s fall impact the Middle East’s geopolitical situation?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Should Xi Jinping attend Donald Trump’s inauguration?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Is the Russian economy Vladimir Putin’s biggest weakness?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How powerful is Hezbollah in Latin America?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To what extent should nuclear armed nations integrate AI into their forces?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Can Papin fix Nissan?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Is South Korea’s political uncertainty hurting its economic prospects?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How will Georgescu perform in a re-running of the first round of Romania’s presidential election?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Has Arce failed to effectively handle Bolivia’s economic crisis?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Choose a Winning Persuasive Speech Topic</title>
      <link>https://zarxstar.github.io/blog/post-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 10:07:47 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zarxstar.github.io/blog/post-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you remember that iconic scene in your favorite movie when the music crescendos, and the hero rises to deliver a speech so electrifying that it leaves everyone in the room either cheering or crying? What makes these moments unforgettable isn’t just the actor’s powerful delivery but also the gripping content of the speech itself. Choosing the right persuasive speech topic can make all the difference when it’s your turn to move an audience. If this sounds like a daunting task, don’t worry. Below, we’ve outlined what makes a persuasive speech topic truly effective and provided some tips to help you craft your own standout moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
